<dashboard version="1.1">
<label>7. Help Working With Fields</label>
<description>Help on how to extract and transform fields</description>
<row>
    <panel ref="helpBanner" app="lame_training"></panel>
  </row>
<row>
  <panel>
    <html>
      <head>
      <style>
      #toc_container {
      background: #f9f9f9 none repeat scroll 0 0;
      border: 1px solid #aaa;
      display: table;
      font-size: 95%;
      margin: auto;
      padding: 20px;
      width: auto;
      }
  
      .toc_title {
      font-weight: 700;
      text-align: left;
      color: #034f84;
      }
  
      #toc_container li, #toc_container ul, #toc_container ul li{
      list-style: outside none none !important;
      }
      
      .mainDiv {
      border: 1px solid lightblue;
      text-align: justify;
      margin: auto;
      width: 75%;
      padding: 20px;
      }
      
      h1 {color: #034f84;}
      h2 {color: #034f84;}
      h3 {color: #034f84;}
      </style>
      </head>
      <body>
        <div class="mainDiv">
        <a name="top"></a>
      <table>
        <tr>
          <td>
            <div id="toc_container">
              <p class="toc_title">Table of Contents</p>
              <ul class="toc_list">
                <li><a href="#fieldAlias">1 Field Aliasing</a></li>
                <li><a href="#calculatedFields">2 Calculated Fields</a></li>
                <li><a href="#fieldExtractions">3 Field Extractions</a></li>
                <li><a href="#fieldTransformations">4 Field Transformations</a></li>
              </ul>
              </div>
          </td>
        </tr>
      </table>
      
      <h1 id="fieldAlias">1 Field Aliasing</h1>
      <p>In your data, you might have groups of events with related field values. To help you search for these groups of fields, you can assign field aliases to their field values.

Field aliases are an alternate name that you assign to a field. You can use that alternate name to search for events that contain that field. A field can have multiple aliases, but a single alias can only apply to one field. For example, the field vendor_action can be an alias of the original fields action or message_type, but not both original fields at the same time. An alias does not replace or remove the original field name.</p>

<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>

<h1 id="calculatedFields">2 Calculated Fields <a href="https://youtu.be/TSr1WjFlgYA" target="_blank"><img src="/static/app/lame_training/youtube.png" width="30" height="30"></img></a></h1>
<p>Calculated fields are fields added to events at search time that perform calculations with the values of two or more fields already present in those events. Use calculated fields as a shortcut for performing repetitive, long, or complex transformations using the eval command.

The eval command enables you to write an expression that uses extracted fields and creates a new field that takes the value that is the result of that expression's evaluation. For more information, see eval.

Eval expressions can be complex. If you need to use a long and complex eval expression on a regular basis, retyping the expression accurately can be tedious.

Calculated fields enable you to define fields with eval expressions. When writing a search, you can cut out the eval expression and reference the field like any other extracted field. The fields are extracted at search time and added to events that include the fields in the eval expressions.</p>


<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>

<h1 id="fieldExtractions">3 Field Extractions <a href="https://youtu.be/5YXjmQpJEjw" target="_blank"><img src="/static/app/lame_training/youtube.png" width="30" height="30"></img></a> </h1>
<p>Use the Field extractions page in Settings to manage search-time field extractions. There are three methods by which you can add search-time field extractions.</p><p>You Can</p> 
<ul>
  <li>Use the field extractor to create extractions. This method is relatively easy and does not require you to understand how regular expressions work.</li>
  <li>Make direct edits to props.conf. You need Splunk Enterprise to use this method.</li>
  <li>Add new field extractions with the Field extractions page.</li>
  
</ul>
<p>The Field extractions page enables you to:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Review the overall set of search-time extractions that you have created or which your permissions enable you to see, for all Apps in your Splunk deployment.</li>
  <li>Create new search-time field extractions.</li>
  <li>Change permissions for field extractions. Field extractions created through the field extractor and the Field extractions page are initially only available to their creators until they are shared with others.</li>
  <li>Delete field extractions, if your app-level permissions enable you to do so, and if they are not default extractions that were delivered with the product. Default knowledge objects cannot be deleted. For more information about deleting knowledge objects, see Disable or delete knowledge objects.
</li>
</ul>
<p>If you have additional write permissions for a particular search-time field extraction, the Field extractions page also enables you to:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Update its regular expression, if it is an inline field extraction.</li>
  <li>Add or delete named extractions that have been defined in transforms.conf or the Field transactions page in Splunk Web, if it uses transactions.</li>
</ul>



<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>

<h1 id="fieldTransformations">4 Field Transformations <a href="https://youtu.be/IcHApZh9eEg" target="_blank"><img src="/static/app/lame_training/youtube.png" width="30" height="30"></img></a></h1>
<p>The Field transformations page in Settings lets you manage transform field extractions, which reside in transforms.conf. Field transforms can be created either through direct edits to transforms.conf or by addition through the Field transformations page.</p>

<p>The Field transformations page enables you to:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Review the overall set of field transforms that you have created or which your permissions enable you to see, for all Apps in your Splunk deployment.</li>
  <li>Create new search-time field transforms. For more information about situations that call for the use of field transforms, see "When to use the Field transformations page," below.</li>
  <li>Update permissions for field transforms. Field transforms created through the Field transformations page are initially only available to their creators until they are shared with others. You can only update field transform permissions if you own the transform, or if your role's permissions enable you to do so.</li>
  <li>Delete field transforms, if your app-level permissions enable you to do so, and if they are not default field transforms that were delivered with the product. Default knowledge objects cannot be deleted. For more information about deleting knowledge objects, see Disable or delete knowledge objects in this manual.</li>
  
</ul>

<p>If you have "write" permissions for a particular field transform, the Field transformations page enables you to:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Update its regular expression and change the key the regular expression applies to.</li>
  <li>Define or update the field transform format.</li>
</ul>
<p>Navigate to the Field transformations page by selecting Settings > Fields > Field transformations.</p>

<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>




    </div>
    </body>
    </html>
  </panel>
</row>
</dashboard>