<dashboard version="1.1">
<label>8. Help Index Management</label>
<description>Help understanding how to create and resize indexes</description>
<row>
    <panel ref="helpBanner" app="lame_training"></panel>
  </row>
<row>
  <panel>
    <html>
      <head>
      <style>
      #toc_container {
      background: #f9f9f9 none repeat scroll 0 0;
      border: 1px solid #aaa;
      display: table;
      font-size: 95%;
      margin: auto;
      padding: 20px;
      width: auto;
      }
  
      .toc_title {
      font-weight: 700;
      text-align: left;
      color: #034f84;
      }
  
      #toc_container li, #toc_container ul, #toc_container ul li{
      list-style: outside none none !important;
      }
      
      .mainDiv {
      border: 1px solid lightblue;
      text-align: justify;
      margin: auto;
      width: 75%;
      padding: 20px;
      }
      
      h1 {color: #034f84;}
      h2 {color: #034f84;}
      h3 {color: #034f84;}
      </style>
      </head>
      <body>
        <div class="mainDiv">
        <a name="top"></a>
      <table>
        <tr>
          <td>
            <div id="toc_container">
              <p class="toc_title">Table of Contents</p>
              <ul class="toc_list">
                <li><a href="#fieldAlias">1 Indexes</a></li>
                <li><a href="#calculatedFields">2 Creating Indexes in Splunk Web</a></li>
                <li><a href="#fieldExtractions">3 Creating Indexes in an App</a></li>
                <li><a href="#fieldTransformations">4 Useful Index Settings</a></li>
              </ul>
              </div>
          </td>
        </tr>
      </table>
      
      <h1 id="fieldAlias">1 Indexes</h1>
      <p>As Splunk Enterprise processes incoming data, it adds the data to indexes. Splunk Enterprise ships with several indexes, and you can create additional indexes as needed.
</p>
<p>A Splunk Enterprise index contains a variety of files. These files fall into two main categories:
</p>
<ul>
  <li>The raw data in compressed form (rawdata)
</li>
<li>Indexes that point to the raw data (index files, also referred to as tsidx files), plus some metadata files
</li>
</ul>

<p>The files reside in directories organized by age. These directories are called buckets. See How Splunk Enterprise stores indexes.
</p>

<p>Splunk Enterprise manages its indexes to facilitate flexible searching and fast data retrieval, eventually archiving them according to a user-configurable schedule. Splunk Enterprise handles everything with flat files; it doesn't require any third-party database software running in the background.</p>
<p>To start indexing, you simply specify the data inputs that you want Splunk Enterprise to index. You can add more inputs at any time, and Splunk Enterprise will begin indexing them as well. See What Splunk Enterprise can index in Getting Data In to learn how to add data inputs.</p>

<p>Splunk Enterprise, by default, puts all user data into a single, preconfigured index. It also employs several other indexes for internal purposes. You can add new indexes and manage existing ones to meet your data requirements.</p>

<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>

<h1 id="calculatedFields">2 Creating Indexes in Splunk Web <a href="https://youtu.be/TSr1WjFlgYA" target="_blank"><img src="/static/app/lame_training/youtube.png" width="30" height="30"></img></a></h1>
<p>The GUI will allow you to create indexes on a specific machine.  If an index is created in the GUI of a search head, that index will not exist on an indexer, it will only exist on that search head.  The same goes for if an index is created on an indexer, the search head does not have that index in its memory so drop down menus WILL NOT reflect those new indexes.</p>


<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>

<h1 id="fieldExtractions">3 Creating Indexes in an App <a href="https://youtu.be/oKk_dCVjb1A" target="_blank"><img src="/static/app/lame_training/youtube.png" width="30" height="30"></img></a></h1>
<p>Under Construction Should Be Complete With Next Version of App</p>



<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>

<h1 id="fieldTransformations">4 Useful Index Settings <a href="https://youtu.be/oKk_dCVjb1A" target="_blank"><img src="/static/app/lame_training/youtube.png" width="30" height="30"></img></a></h1>
<p>Under Construction Should Be Complete With Next Version of App</p>

<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>




    </div>
    </body>
    </html>
  </panel>
</row>
</dashboard>