<dashboard version="1.1">
<label>6. Help Lookup Management</label>
<description>Help with lookups</description>
<row>
    <panel ref="helpBanner" app="search"></panel>
  </row>
<row>
  <panel>
    <html>
      <head>
      <style>
      #toc_container {
      background: #f9f9f9 none repeat scroll 0 0;
      border: 1px solid #aaa;
      display: table;
      font-size: 95%;
      margin: auto;
      padding: 20px;
      width: auto;
      }
  
      .toc_title {
      font-weight: 700;
      text-align: left;
      color: #034f84;
      }
  
      #toc_container li, #toc_container ul, #toc_container ul li{
      list-style: outside none none !important;
      }
      
      .mainDiv {
      border: 1px solid lightblue;
      text-align: justify;
      margin: auto;
      width: 75%;
      padding: 20px;
      }
      
      h1 {color: #034f84;}
      h2 {color: #034f84;}
      h3 {color: #034f84;}
      </style>
      </head>
      <body>
        <div class="mainDiv">
        <a name="top"></a>
      <table>
        <tr>
          <td>
            <div id="toc_container">
              <p class="toc_title">Table of Contents</p>
              <ul class="toc_list">
                <li><a href="#intro">1 Splunk Lookups</a></li>
                <li><a href="#types">2 Types of Lookups</a></li>
                <li><a href="#csv">2.1 CSV Lookups</a></li>
                <li><a href="#kv">2.2 KV Lookups</a></li>
                <li><a href="#geospatial">2.3 GeoSpatial Lookups</a></li>
                <li><a href="#definition">3. Lookup Definition</a></li>
                <li><a href="#automatic">4. Automatic Lookup Definition</a></li>
                <li><a href="#subsearches">5 Using Lookups in SubSearches</a></li>
              </ul>
              </div>
          </td>
        </tr>
      </table>
      
      <h1 id="intro">1 Splunk Lookups</h1>
      <p>Lookups enrich your event data by adding field-value combinations from lookup tables. Splunk software uses lookups to match field-value combinations in your event data with field-value combinations in external lookup tables. If Splunk software finds those field-value combinations in your lookup table, Splunk software will append the corresponding field-value combinations from the table to the events in your search.</p>

<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>

<h1 id="types">2 Types of Lookups </h1>
<p>There are multiple methods for using lookups: </p>
<ul>
  <li>CSV lookups</li>
  <li>KV Lookups</li>
  <li>GeoSpatial Lookups</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>

<h1 id="intro">2.1 CSV Lookups <a href="https://youtu.be/SfEDJj7Jgpg" target="_blank"><img src="/static/app/lame_training/youtube.png" width="30" height="30"></img></a></h1>
<p>Populates your events with fields pulled from CSV files. Also referred to as a static lookup because CSV files represent static tables of data. Each column in a CSV table is interpreted as the potential values of a field. Use CSV lookups when you have small sets of data that is relatively static.</p>

<p><b>Upload Lookup</b></p>
  <p>Steps</p>
<ul>

  <li>  Select Settings > Lookups to go to the Lookups manager page.</li>
  <li>  Click Add new next to Lookup table files.</li>
  <li>  Select a Destination app from the drop-down list.</li>
  <li>  Click Choose File to look for the CSV file to upload.</li>
  <li>  Enter the destination filename. This is the name the lookup table file will have on the Splunk server. If you are uploading a gzipped CSV file, enter a filename ending in ".gz". If you are uploading a plaintext CSV file, use a filename ending in ".csv".</li>
  <li>  Click Save.</li>
</ul>
  <p>By default, the Splunk software saves your CSV file in your user directory for the Destination app: $SPLUNK_HOME/etc/users/username/app_name/lookups/. </p>
    
    
    
    



<p><b>Output Lookup</b></p>
<ul>
  <li>Export the unique list to a lookup called MyInventory.csv - This CSV does not have to exist.</li>
  <li>index=lame_training sourcetype=lame_conn | stats count by src_ip, dest_ip | outputlookup MyInventory.csv </li>
  <li>Export the unique list and append it to a lookup called MyInventory.csv </li>
  <li>index=lame_training sourcetype=lame_conn | stats count by src_ip, dest_ip | outputlookup MyInventory.csv append=true </li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>

<h1 id="host">2.2 KV Lookups <a href="https://youtu.be/-UP4xzdzwXI" target="_blank"><img src="/static/app/lame_training/youtube.png" width="30" height="30"></img></a></h1>
<p>Matches fields in your events to fields in a KV Store collection and outputs corresponding fields in that collection to your events. Use a KV Store lookup when you have a large lookup table or a table that is updated often. </p>

<p><b>Upload Lookup</b></p>
<p><b>Output Lookup</b></p>
<ul>
  <li>Export the unique list to a pre-existing KV store called MyInventory </li>
  <li>index=lame_training sourcetype=lame_conn | stats count by src_ip, dest_ip | outputlookup MyInventory </li>
  <li>Export the unique list and append it to a lookup called MyInventory </li>
  <li>index=lame_training sourcetype=lame_conn | stats count by src_ip, dest_ip | outputlookup MyInventory append=true </li>
</ul>

<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>

<h1 id="host">2.3 GeoSpatial Lookups</h1>
<p>A geospatial lookup matches location coordinates in your events to geographic feature collections in a KMZ or KML file and outputs fields to your events that provide corresponding geographic feature information encoded in the KMZ or KML, like country, state, or county names. Use a geospatial lookup to create a query that Splunk software uses to configure a choropleth map. </p>



<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>

<h1 id="definition">3 Lookup Definitions <a href="https://youtu.be/1BdnU51wPfs" target="_blank"><img src="/static/app/lame_training/youtube.png" width="30" height="30"></img></a></h1>
<p>A lookup definition provides a lookup name and a path to find the lookup table. Lookup definitions can include extra settings such as matching rules, or restrictions on the fields that the lookup is allowed to match. One lookup table can have multiple lookup definitions.</p>

<p>All lookup types require a lookup definition. After you create a lookup definition you can invoke the lookup in a search with the lookup command. </p>

<ol>
  <li>Select Settings > Lookups.</li>
  <li>Click Add new next to Lookup definitions.</li>
  <li>Select a Destination app from the drop-down list.</li>
  <li>Your lookup table file is saved in the directory where the application resides. For example: $SPLUNK_HOME/etc/users/username/app_name/lookups/.</li>
  <li>Give your lookup definition a unique Name.</li>
  <li>Select File-based as the lookup Type.</li>
  <li>Select the Lookup file from the drop-down list. For a CSV lookup, the file extension must be .csv.</li>
  <li>(Optional) If the CSV file contains time fields, make the CSV lookup time-bounded by selecting the Configure time-based lookup check box</li>
</ol>
  <img src="/static/app/lame_training/TimeBasedInfo.png" width="800" height="400"></img>
<ol>
  <li>(Optional) To define advanced options for your lookup, select the Advanced options check box.</li>
</ol>
<img src="/static/app/lame_training/AdvancedOptions.png" width="800" height="400"></img>








<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>

<h1 id="automatic">4 Automatic Lookups <a href="https://youtu.be/1BdnU51wPfs" target="_blank"><img src="/static/app/lame_training/youtube.png" width="30" height="30"></img></a></h1>
<p>Use automatic lookups to apply a lookup to all searches at search time. After you define an automatic lookup for a lookup definition, you do not need to manually invoke it in searches with the lookup command.</p>


<ol>
  <li>In Splunk Web, select Settings > Lookups.</li>
  <li>Under Actions for Automatic Lookups, click Add new.</li>
   <li>Select the Destination app.</li>
    <li>Give your automatic lookup a unique Name.</li>
     <li>Select the Lookup table that you want to use in your fields lookup.</li> 
     <li>This is the name of the lookup definition that you defined on the Lookup Definition page.</li>
     <li>In the Apply to menu, select a host, source, or source type value to apply the lookup and give it a name in the named field.</li>
       <li>Under Lookup input fields provide one or more pairs of input fields.</li>
         <li>The first field is the field in the lookup table that you want to match. The second field is a field from your events that matches the lookup table field. For example, you can have an ip_address field in your events that matches an ip field in the lookup table. So you would enter ip = ip_address in the automatic lookup definition.</li>
           <li>Under Lookup output fields provide one or more pairs of output fields.</li>
           <li>The first field is the corresponding field that you want to output to events. The second field is the name that the output field should have in your events. For example, the lookup table may have a field named country that you may want to output to your events as ip_city. So you would enter country=ip_city in the automatic lookup definition.</li>
           <li>To avoid creating automatic lookup reference cycles, do not leave the Lookup output fields blank.</li>
           <li>Select Overwrite field values to overwrite existing field values in events when the lookup runs. If you do not select this checkbox, the Splunk software does not apply the lookup to events where the output fields already exist.</li>
           <li>Note: This is equivalent to configuring your fields lookup in props.conf.</li>
           <li>Click Save.</li>
</ol>

<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>


<h1 id="subsearches">5 Using Lookups in Subsearches </h1>
<p>Lookups can be used as a subsearch to restrict a search down to a list of values.</p>


<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>



    </div>
    </body>
    </html>
  </panel>
</row>
</dashboard>