<dashboard version="1.1">
<label>8. Help Index Management</label>
<description>Help understanding how to create and resize indexes</description>
<row>
    <panel ref="helpBanner" app="search"></panel>
  </row>
<row>
  <panel>
    <html>
      <head>
      <style>
      #toc_container {
      background: #f9f9f9 none repeat scroll 0 0;
      border: 1px solid #aaa;
      display: table;
      font-size: 95%;
      margin: auto;
      padding: 20px;
      width: auto;
      }
  
      .toc_title {
      font-weight: 700;
      text-align: left;
      color: #034f84;
      }
  
      #toc_container li, #toc_container ul, #toc_container ul li{
      list-style: outside none none !important;
      }
      
      .mainDiv {
      border: 1px solid lightblue;
      text-align: justify;
      margin: auto;
      width: 75%;
      padding: 20px;
      }
      
      h1 {color: #034f84;}
      h2 {color: #034f84;}
      h3 {color: #034f84;}
      </style>
      </head>
      <body>
        <div class="mainDiv">
        <a name="top"></a>
      <table>
        <tr>
          <td>
            <div id="toc_container">
              <p class="toc_title">Table of Contents</p>
              <ul class="toc_list">
                <li><a href="#intro">1 Introduction</a></li>
                <li><a href="#indicator_hunting">2 Indicator Hunting</a>
                  <ul>
                    <li><a href="#search_CSIHA">2.1 Search Using the CS Indicator Hunting App</a>
                      <ul>
                        <li><a href="#search_CSIHA_lookup">2.1.1 To Search for multiple indicators using a Lookup</a></li>
                        <li><a href="#search_CSIHA_adhoc">2.1.2 To Search for Ad Hoc Indicators</a></li>
                      </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li><a href="#search_custom">2.2 Search Using A Custom Query</a></li>
                  </ul>
                </li>
              <li><a href="#information_protection">3 Information Protection</a></li>
              <li><a href="#references">4 Appendix A - References</a></li>
              </ul>
              </div>
          </td>
        </tr>
      </table>
      
      <h1 id="intro">1 Introduction</h1>
      <p>The CyberSentry (CS) Splunk Architecture allows for real-time and historical indicator searching. Analysts
can use various techniques to search for historical indicators of compromise. Real-time searches are part
of the automated indicator detection process. See the CS Indicator Processing work instruction (Ref C)
for further details. CyberSentry Splunk is configured to summarize key Corelight log data making
searching for indicators simple and efficient. Historical indicator searches can be performed from three
locations:</p>
<ul>
  <li>the Central Summary Data – primarily used for reduced impact to mission partner sites</li>
  <li>the Central Search Head – searches all customer sites concurrently – can impact mission partner site bandwidth</li>
  <li>directly on each mission partner site – minimal impact to customer but must be done on each mission partner site search head at https://splunk.site[x].cs.dhs:8000.</li>
</ul>
<p>Note: (Replace [x] with the mission partner site number)</p>
<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>

<h1 id="indicator_hunting">2 Indicator Hunting</h1>
<p>Although an indicator can be any literal string within the data, the CS Splunk environment has been
optimized to search for many well-known indicator types. The Science of Searching for indicators in
Splunk Data (Ref B) provides more details on this optimization. There are many indicators within CS data
made available, including the following:</p>
<table>
  <tr>
    <td>
      <ul>
        <li>x509 Certificate Details</li>
        <li>Media Access Control Address</li>
        <li>HTTP Headers</li>
        <li>Email From: Addresses</li>
        <li>Email Subject: Line</li>
        <li>File Name</li>
        <li>File Hash md5</li>
        <li>File Hash sha1</li>
        <li>File Hash sha256</li>
      </ul>
    </td>
    <td>
      <ul>
        <li>SSH Host Key</li>
        <li><a href="https://github.com/salesforce/hassh" target="_blank">HASSH md5 Fingerprints (Ref E)</a></li>
        <li>Domain Name</li>
        <li>IPv4 Address</li>
        <li>IPv6 Address</li>
        <li><a href="https://github.com/salesforce/ja3" target="_blank">JA3 md5 Fingerprints (Ref D)</a></li>
        <li>File Mime Type</li>
        <li>URL</li>
        <li>Account User Names</li>
      </ul>
    </td>
  </tr>
</table>
<p>Below are the three options for indicator searching ordered by efficiency:</p>
  <ol>
    <li>Search for several indicators using a lookup in the <a href="/app/CS_Indicator_Hunting" target="_blank">CS Indicator Hunting App</a></li>
    <li>Search for ad-hoc indicators using the <a href="/app/CS_Indicator_Hunting" target="_blank">CS Indicator Hunting App</a></li>
    <li>Search for ad-hoc indicators using the <a href="/app/search" target="_blank">Search and Reporting App</a></li>
  </ol>
<p>The CS Indicator Hunting App (IOCH App) streamlines the most common IOC Search use cases to reduce time to effective detection, analysis, and reporting. 
The IOCH App is available on the Central Search Head only.  The CS Splunk environment tracks all indicators that have been searched during the automated process. 
This record of previous searches is checked when an analyst uses the IOCH App to search for indicators. If the indicators have already been searched for, 
the results will return based on what was already found. This validation minimizes Splunk processing overhead and redundant analysis efforts.</p>
<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>

<h2 id="search_CSIHA">2.1 Search Using the CS Indicator Hunting App</h2>
<p>The CS Indicator Hunting App (IOCH App) removes the need for an analyst to craft complex Splunk queries. An analyst can upload a csv file containing 
indicators or search for a small set of ad hoc indicators using the IOCH App search interface.</p>
<img src="/static/app/CyberSentry_Training/ioch_dashboard.png" alt="graphic of IOCH App search interface" width="75%" style="border:1px solid lightblue"></img>
<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>

<h3 id="search_CSIHA_lookup">2.1.1 To Search for multiple indicators using a Lookup</h3>
<ol>
  <li>To upload a new set of indicators to search for open the IOCH App and  click on the appropriate create a lookup.</li>
  <li>Splunk will open a new tab that will allow you to copy and paste the list of indicators into one column and provide a name for the report.  
  The report field is optional. You can also manually enter your indicators or upload an existing csv file (the csv must be in the specified format). This process creates the lookup table. </li>
  <li>Select the target data set. The target can be one or more mission partners or by industry sector. </li>
  <li>Once the lookup is created and a target selected, a search processing language (SPL) query will be dynamically generated that the analyst can run. 
  Return to the previous tab and follow the instructions.</li>
  <li>When the link is clicked, Splunk will redirect to a search page with a prepopulated SPL query. Select a timeframe and click Search. Splunk will start 
  the search using the data you provided in the lookup, the target and the timeframe. </li>
</ol>
<p>Often it doesn’t make sense to use a lookup because an Analyst is only looking for one or two indicators.  There is an option in the IOCH App for Ad Hoc Search.</p>
<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>

<h3 id="search_CSIHA_adhoc">2.1.2 To Search for Ad Hoc Indicators</h3>
<ol>
  <li>To best use this page, choose the time frame that you want to search within.</li>
  <li>Then choose the indicator type from the dropdown. </li>
  <li>Enter the indicator into the indicator text box.</li>
  <li>Select a timeframe.</li>
  <li>Click Search. The IOCH App will search targeted fields based on the indicator type selected.</li>
</ol>
<img src="/static/app/CyberSentry_Training/adhocDashboard.png" alt="graphic of IOCH App ad hoc search interface" width="75%" style="border:1px solid lightblue"></img>
<p>Note: Wildcard searches can be used on the indicators with the use of an asterisk *</p>
<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>

<h2 id="search_custom">2.2 Search Using A Custom Query</h2>
<p>The least efficient method for searching for indicators is using a custom SPL query. This should only be performed by experienced analysts because it can 
generate an excessive burden on the CS Splunk environment and impact the work of other analysts. Analysts should check the bro_intel index for the indicator 
they are searching for prior to searching the CS data. The bro_intel index exists on the Central Search Head only. If the indicator(s) are in the bro_intel index, 
the automated indicator search processes is already looking for the indicator(s) and the analyst should not search for them again.</p>
<ol>
  <li>Use the Search and Reporting App within Splunk Central or a specific site Search Head.</li>
  <li>Craft the query using the <a href="https://djangocas.dev/blog/splunk/splunk-search-best-practices-for-better-performance-response-time/" target="_blank">Splunk best practices (Ref A)</a>:
    <ul>
      <li>Time is the most efficient filter</li>
      <li>Limit the number of events retrieved, e.g. head command or event sampling</li>
      <li>Specify one or more index values at the beginning of your search string
        <ul>
          <li>specify multiple index values in a search</li>
          <li>use a wildcard (*) in index values</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>Include as many search terms as possible</li>
      <li>Make your search terms as specific as possible</li>
      <li>Inclusion is generally better than exclusion (NOT)</li>
      <li>Filter as early as possible</li>
      <li>Avoid using wildcards at the beginning or middle of a string</li>
      <li>When possible, use OR instead of wildcards</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Set the time window to a discrete timeframe. “All Time” should not be used.</li>
  <li>Click Search</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>

<h1 id="information_protection">3 Information Protection</h1>
<p>Indicator hunting is a fundamental component of the Analyst’s workflow; therefore, the CS Splunk is architected for maximum indicator search capability. 
This flexibility presents a risk that an analyst will upload sensitive indicators into the Splunk environment. In some cases, Splunk search artifacts may be 
accessible by mission partners. Analysts can mitigate this risk by seeking Lead approval prior to searching for <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/tlp" target="_blank">TLP AMBER or TLP RED (Ref F)</a> indicators.</p>
<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>
<h1 id="references">4 Appendix A – References</h1>
<ol type="A">
  <li>Splunk Search Best Practices - <a href="https://djangocas.dev/blog/splunk/splunk-search-best-practices-for-better-performance-response-time/" target="_blank">https://djangocas.dev/blog/splunk/splunk-search-best-practices-for-better-performance-response-time/</a></li>
  <li>The Science of Searching for Indicators in Splunk Data - INL CyberSentry Sharepoint</li>
  <li>CS Indicator Processing Work Instruction - INL CyberSentry Sharepoint</li>
  <li>JA3 Fingerprinting - <a href="https://github.com/salesforce/ja3" target="_blank">https://github.com/salesforce/ja3</a></li>
  <li>HASSH Fingerprinting - <a href="https://github.com/salesforce/hassh" target="_blank">https://github.com/salesforce/hassh</a></li>
  <li>CISA Traffic Light Protocol - <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/tlp" target="_blank">https://www.cisa.gov/tlp</a></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="#top">Back to top of page</a></p>
    </div>
    </body>
    </html>
  </panel>
</row>
</dashboard>